<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ASCII"?>
<gra:ServiceMetadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:gra="http://it.ojp.gov/gsp/services/1.0.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://it.ojp.gov/gsp/services/1.0.0 Metadata.xsd">
  <gra:ServiceIdentification>
    <gra:ServiceFullNameText>SORNA Inter-Jurisdiction Relocation Service</gra:ServiceFullNameText>
    <gra:ServiceID></gra:ServiceID>
    <gra:ServiceURI></gra:ServiceURI>
    <gra:ServiceNameAbbreviationText>SIRS</gra:ServiceNameAbbreviationText>
  </gra:ServiceIdentification>
  <gra:ServiceDescription>
    <gra:ServicePurposeText>When a registered sex offender relocates from one SORNA jurisdiction to another SORNA jurisdiction, SIRS will enable the sharing of information that assists the jurisdictions with identifying, monitoring, and enforcing the offender&#x2019;s registration requirements associated with the relocation process.</gra:ServicePurposeText>
    <gra:ServiceScopeDescriptionText>&#x2022; The sex offender&#x2019;s initial intent to relocate, along with information about the offender (Relocation Package).

&#x2022; The receiving jurisdiction&#x2019;s acknowledgement of its receipt of the sending jurisdiction&#x2019;s Relocation Package, together with a message describing the receiving jurisdiction&#x2019;s registration requirements (Relocation Confirmation Notification).

&#x2022; The sex offender&#x2019;s compliance with the new jurisdiction&#x2019;s registration requirements (Relocation Compliance Notification).

&#x2022; The sex offender&#x2019;s failure to contact the new jurisdiction (Did Not Report Notification).

&#x2022; The sending jurisdiction&#x2019;s resolution of a relocation notice (Relocation Cancelled Notification).

&#x2022; The sending jurisdiction&#x2019;s request for assistance from the USMS National Sex Offender Targeting Center (Relocation Package).

The following capabilities fall outside the scope of SIRS:

&#x2022; Mechanisms for a sex offender to register with a SORNA jurisdiction.

&#x2022; Disclosure of sex offenders&#x2019; information to the public.

&#x2022; Exchanges of information between a SORNA jurisdiction&#x2019;s registering agency and local law enforcement agencies.

&#x2022; Creation of new criminal charges against a sex offender for failure to comply with registration requirements.

&#x2022; Maintenance of data in criminal history repositories.
</gra:ServiceScopeDescriptionText>
    <gra:ServiceDescriptionSummaryText>SIRS provides offender information and notices between stakeholders to track the offender&#x2019;s compliance with SORNA registration requirements.</gra:ServiceDescriptionSummaryText>
    <gra:ServiceDescriptionText>Today, several mechanisms are being used to communicate information among SORNA jurisdictions when a sex offender relocates.  It is challenging for a SORNA jurisdiction to share the requirements for interacting with another SORNA jurisdiction.  In particular:

&#xf0fc; What is the most effective medium for the initial notification?  E-mail, fax, a telephone call, or an electronic message delivered by a proprietary record management system that both agencies use?  

&#xf0fc; What is the best method for delivering documents?  Can scanned images be e-mailed?  If so, what are the size limits?

&#xf0fc; What data are required by the receiving jurisdiction?  Do they have a hardcopy or online form or checklist?

&#xf0fc; What are the other jurisdiction&#x2019;s expectations about subsequent communications?  

SIRS builds on the progress made by the SORNA Exchange Portal in defining a messaging process and protocol in the form of a service.  The service applies national standards and specifies interfaces that can be implemented in a wide variety of technical environments.  Having an interoperable standard for interjurisdictional information exchange and notifications will enable SORNA registration jurisdictions to achieve greater efficiency through automation.  

SIRS provides the messaging required between SORNA stakeholders when a sex offender relocates to a new SORNA jurisdiction.  The service provides offender information and notices between stakeholders to track the offender&#x2019;s status and compliance with SORNA registration requirements.</gra:ServiceDescriptionText>
    <gra:ServiceDescriptionKeywordText>SORNA, SIRS, Sex Offender, Registration, Relocation</gra:ServiceDescriptionKeywordText>
    <gra:ServiceCapabilities>
      <gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>Positive identification of an offender (e.g., biometric data, photographs, federal or state identifiers). Information that assists in locating an offender (e.g., home, work, or school addresses; vehicle data; contact information such as telephone numbers, e-mail addresses, and social media screen names and other identifiers).</gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>
      <gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>Information about the offender's underlying criminal conviction(s) and offense(s) (e.g., court documents, statutory definitions of the crime's elements).  Other information relevant to a risk assessment (e.g., data about victims, mental health diagnoses and treatments, substance abuse history).</gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>
      <gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>Notification of the status of the offender's registration (i.e., whether registration is required in the receiving jurisdiction, and, if so, whether the offender complied with those requirements).</gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>
      <gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>Engagement of the United States Marshals Service in locating absconders or non-compliant offenders.</gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>
      <gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>Contact information for the SORNA jurisdictions' registration agencies.</gra:CapabilityDescriptionText>
    </gra:ServiceCapabilities>
    <gra:ServiceRealWorldEffects>
      <gra:RealWorldEffectDescriptionText>Successful tracking of an offender through the SORNA inter-jurisdiction relocation process.</gra:RealWorldEffectDescriptionText>
      <gra:RealWorldEffectDescriptionText>System automation of manual, time-consuming, and non-standardized processes.</gra:RealWorldEffectDescriptionText>
    </gra:ServiceRealWorldEffects>
    <gra:SecurityClassificationText>SBU</gra:SecurityClassificationText>
    <gra:ServiceDependencies/>
    <gra:IEPDReferences>
      <gra:IEPDReference>
        <gra:IEPDName>SORNA Relocation IEPD</gra:IEPDName>
      </gra:IEPDReference>
    </gra:IEPDReferences>
  </gra:ServiceDescription>
  <gra:VersionInformation>
    <gra:MajorVersion>1</gra:MajorVersion>
    <gra:MinorVersion>0</gra:MinorVersion>
    <gra:RevisionVersion>0</gra:RevisionVersion>
    <gra:CreationDate>2012-06-08</gra:CreationDate>
    <gra:LifecycleStatus>Operational/Production</gra:LifecycleStatus>
  </gra:VersionInformation>
  <gra:RelatedOrganizationInformation>
    <gra:Organization>
      <gra:OrganizationName>Office of Sex Offender Sentencing, Monitoring, Apprehending, Registering, and Tracking, Office of Justice Programs</gra:OrganizationName>
      <gra:OrganizationAcronym>SMART, OJP</gra:OrganizationAcronym>
      <gra:OrganizationFullAddressText>810 Seventh Street NW, Washington, DC 20531</gra:OrganizationFullAddressText>
      <gra:OrganizationWebSiteURL>http://www.ojp.usdoj.gov/smart/</gra:OrganizationWebSiteURL>
      <gra:OrganizationRoleDescriptionText>Owner</gra:OrganizationRoleDescriptionText>
      <gra:OrganizationRoleDetailedDescriptionText>Owner</gra:OrganizationRoleDetailedDescriptionText>
      <gra:OrganizationPointOfContact>
        <gra:ContactPersonName>TBD</gra:ContactPersonName>
        <gra:ContactPersonEmailID>getsmart@usdoj.gov</gra:ContactPersonEmailID>
        <gra:ContactPersonPhoneNumberID>202-514-4689</gra:ContactPersonPhoneNumberID>
        <gra:ContactPersonAddress>810 Seventh Street NW, Washington, DC 20531</gra:ContactPersonAddress>
      </gra:OrganizationPointOfContact>
    </gra:Organization>
  </gra:RelatedOrganizationInformation>
  <gra:ServiceLevelAgreements>
    <gra:ServicePolicyAndContracts>
      <gra:ApplicablePoliciesIndicator>true</gra:ApplicablePoliciesIndicator>
      <gra:ApplicablePolicies>
        <gra:PolicyText>CJIS Security Policy</gra:PolicyText>
      </gra:ApplicablePolicies>
      <gra:ApplicableContractsIndicator>false</gra:ApplicableContractsIndicator>
      <gra:ApplicableContracts/>
      <gra:ApplicableAgreementsIndicator>false</gra:ApplicableAgreementsIndicator>
      <gra:ApplicableAgreements/>
      <gra:ApplicableUmbrellaAgreementsIndicator>false</gra:ApplicableUmbrellaAgreementsIndicator>
      <gra:ApplicableUmbrellaAgreements/>
    </gra:ServicePolicyAndContracts>
    <gra:PerformanceMetrics>
      <gra:ServiceResponseTime>P1Y2M3DT10H30M</gra:ServiceResponseTime>
      <gra:ServiceAverageThroughput></gra:ServiceAverageThroughput>
      <gra:ServiceMaximumThroughput></gra:ServiceMaximumThroughput>
      <gra:ServiceAvailability></gra:ServiceAvailability>
    </gra:PerformanceMetrics>
    <gra:ServiceUsageDetails>
      <gra:ApprovalRequiredIndicator>false</gra:ApprovalRequiredIndicator>
      <gra:LicensingRequiredIndicator>false</gra:LicensingRequiredIndicator>
      <gra:LicensingAgreement/>
      <gra:ServiceCost>
        <gra:UsageCostAmount>0.0</gra:UsageCostAmount>
        <gra:UsageUnitCostAmount>0.0</gra:UsageUnitCostAmount>
        <gra:CreationCostAmount>0.0</gra:CreationCostAmount>
      </gra:ServiceCost>
    </gra:ServiceUsageDetails>
  </gra:ServiceLevelAgreements>
</gra:ServiceMetadata>